AnnMarie F. Pigna-Torres

(908) 499-9622 AnnMarieTorres@Outlook.com

Professional Profile:

Accomplished Software Engineer with experience in Xamarin, C#, and XAML cross-platform iOS, Android mobile application development, and Windows forms software. Skilled at developing Web Applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JavaScript libraries. Excellent programming, problem solving, analytical, and interpersonal skills.

Technical Knowledge:

→ MS Visual Studio	→ C#	→ ASP.Net	→ WCF
→ Xamarin	→ ADO.Net	→ CSS	→ AJAX
→ Sublime Text	→ Microsoft SQL	→ HTML	→ Express
→ JSON	→ SQL/PL SQL	→ XAML/XML	→ Jade
→ TypeScript	→ Angular 2	→ Node.js	→ MongoDB
→ Bootstrap	→ JQuery	→ JavaScript	→ SOAP

Professional History:

Kaizen Technologies, Edison, New Jersey

March 2016 – September 2016

Independent Consultant

- → Enhancing my existing C# skills with WPF, ASP.net, WinForms, WCF, SOAP, AJAX, XAML, ADO.net, and MVC
- → Increasing my skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Angular 2, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Jade, MongoDB, and TypeScript.
- → Developing my SQL server management skills with BI analysis using Microsoft SQL, and Excel

Phunctor, Manhattan, New York

July 2015 – October 2015

Freelance Software Engineer (short-term project)

- → Developed cross-platform iOS and Android mobile applications
- → Designed applications using Xamarin Studio using C# in PCLs and shared libraries.
- → Used 95% shared code cutting development and debugging time by 50%
- → Debugged and tested applications using emulators, simulators, and actual devices.
- → Used Xamarin Forms ensuring native look and feel across devices
- → Conducted trial runs of programs and software applications to ensure they produced the desired information and that the instructions are correct.
- → Developed message application using C# mono class libraries

Silicon Network Solutions, Elizabeth, New Jersey

June 2009 – July 2011

Freelance Software Engineer

- → Upgraded Web Sites with current information and business data.
- → Designed new company custom websites.

Linkedin.com/in/AnnMarieTorres

Github.com/AnnMarieTorres

- → Modified existing software to correct errors, or to improve its performance.
- → Assisted in rollout of new software packages on company machines including upgrades and training assistance.
- → Managed documentation on software changes to ensure all new updates where included

CNG Internet, Tinton Falls, New Jersey

June 2007 – June 2009

Software Engineer

- → Developed programs using Registry Keys.
- → Created Active Directory automation software.
- → Researched, designed, wrote, and debugged new software programs.
- → Tested software applications for quality assurance.
- → Prepared application functionality of software functions.
- → Maintained systems by monitoring and correcting software defects.

Verizon, Shrewsbury, New Jersey

June 1998 – June 2007

Consultant/Fraud

- → Investigated customer accounts for fraudulent activity, and followed up on suspicious fraudulent phone usage behaviors.
- → Operated a computer terminal, including accessing multiple systems to retrieve and update customer service data while simultaneously negotiating with customers and/or company employees.
- → Met or exceeded deadlines that satisfied customer requirements and needs promptly, accurately, and pleasantly, realizing that some customers may be irate.
- → Assisted customers, by telephone, to negotiate collection of overdue active or final bills and advised customers of service interruption for non-payment of bills.
- → Completed clerical activities associated with collection of overdue bills and referral of accounts to collection agents, meeting and exceeding corporate requirements for all collection related objectives.
- → Prepared and transmitted denials, restores, and disconnects for non-payment or fraudulent activity.
- → Verify and assess customer credit information.

Volunteer:

Blue Economics, Manhattan, New York

June 2015 – Present

Developer

→ Assisted in developing a front end website for a non-profit to assist individuals who are looking for new careers.

Education:

DeVry College of Technology, North Brunswick, New Jersey

October 2004

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems

GPA: 3.9 – Summa Cum Laude